All right. So, here we'll go through the second video of how to break into the field.
现在是第二个解决方案视频 针对如何入门这一问题
So, essentially if this was our question of interest,
如果这是我们感兴趣的问题
what steps could we go through to analyze the data and try to answer it.
应该如何分析数据得出结论呢?
So, the first question is,
第一个问题是
in order to understand how to break into the field,
为了理解如何入门这个问题
we'll look at the CousinEducation field,
需要先理解 CousinEducation 特征列
use the schema data set to answer the question,
使用 schema 数据集来回答这一问题
and write a function called get description that takes
完成这个名为 get_description 的函数
the schema and the column as a string and returns the description for that column.
其参数为 schema DataFrame 以及字符串形式的列名 返回对该列的描述
So, basically schema is the data set that we read in up here.
schema 就是这里读入的数据集
So, and in this case we read into data sets.
这里读入了两个数据集
Again, a whole bunch of libraries and this test PI file that's going to run our code,
再次导入了很多库 以及 test1.py 测试文件
and make sure that it works the way it's supposed to.
帮助我们检查代码
But we also have the schema data set that we're going to be working with.
schema 是接下来会用到的数据集
So, what might be useful to do is,
我们可以在这里
again if we create,
再次插入一个单元格
and we just take a quick look at what the schema data set looks like.
快速浏览一下 schema 数据集
So, you'll see there's a column and a question,
可以看到 Column 列以及 Question 列
and basically what we want to do is,
我们要做的是
we want to be able to take the column as a string,
输入列名字符串
and then return the description.
返回其对应的描述
So, here's the description,
描述就是 Question 列中的内容
and the column names over here.
而列名就在这里的 Column 列中
So, that means, we're going to
也就是说
take schema which is getting passed in as an argument here.
使用 schema 参数
It's one of the inputs.
也就是其中一个输入参数
And we want the column to be equal to the column name.
我们需要 Column 等于 column_name
And when that's true,
如果判断为 True
we basically want to grab
就是要筛选出 schema 中 Column 列的值等于 column_name 的数据
and then just give back the question part.
返回该行数据对应的 Question 列的内容
So, if you imagine what this is doing and here is it saying,
再来看一下代码具体的作用
"I want you to go into the schema I want you to grab the column with
我想要到 schema 数据集中 找到 Column 列中
this column name that you pass me and then give me the description back out of that."
等于输入的列名的数据 然后给出其对应的描述部分
So hopefully, this works.
希望这是对的
And if it does then we should,
如果是对的……
oh, it didn't work.
噢 有错误
Shema, I have shema somewhere, schema, cool.
某个 schema 拼错了
So, it says that's
好了 可以看到
the respondent ID number and we can check it against the solution here.
这个描述是问卷参与者的 ID 可以对照答案检查一下
Oh no, it didn't work.
噢 又不行
So, series objects are mutable thus they cannot be hashed.
这里的报错说 Series 是可变类型 不能进行哈希
So, we can go back here and if we look at how to break in the field and the solution,
我们可以回到这里 打开 solution 文件
and we look at this.
看一下答案
Oh, they turn them into a list and then pull it,
他们先把结果转换成列表 然后再提取
so back here. Try this again.
回到刚才的练习中 再来试一下
So, they suggest doing this as a list and then pulling.
答案说要转换为列表再提取
So, then it's only that part.
然后就只有描述字符串的部分了
That's weird. Why?
奇怪 为什么呢?
Schema, schema column
试一下 schema[schema['Column'] == 'Country']
It's now pulling that.
然后再选出对应的 Question 列
And it gives me that weird thing back.
这样就返回了之前奇怪的数据形式
And if I ask for a list,
如果将其转换为列表
then it only gives me the string back.
里面就只剩了一个字符串
Gives me like a Pandas Dataframe and if I pass it to a list,
给定一个类似 Pandas DataFrame 的数据 将其转换成列表
then it only gives me that.
就得出了这样的结果
And so then, the zero just pulls that string out of there.
这样索引 0 就能将其中的字符串提取出来
Tricky, that one was kind of tricky.
这句代码比较绕
So, then the question we've been focused on is,
好了 我们想要解决的问题是
how to break into the field,
如何入门技术领域
which is this column here.
也就是这一列 (CousinEducation)
And so, here's a description of that column.
这里就可以看到其对应的描述了
So, we could read through this to understand better,
仔细阅读这段文字
like why this is a useful thing to use to help us break into the field.
可以更好地理解 为什么该列对了解如何入门有帮助
This core set value says,
这里的 core_ed_vals 表示
"Provide a pandas series of accounts for each in the CousinEducation and then,
包含 CousinEducation 列每种类别数量的 Pandas Series
make sure it looks right."
确保数据展示正确
So, this is just df (Cousin Education ) and then.value_counts.
代码是 df['CousinEducation'].value_counts()
It sure looks okay.
要确保结果是可行的
So you'll notice, so this kind of looks bad.
你会发现 结果看上去并不太好
Like all of these things,
比如这些
if somebody suggested more than one thing,
如果一个人给出多条建议
it puts all of them together.
这些建议就都被放在一起了
So, this person suggested three different things,
比如 这个人给出了三条建议
this person suggested four different things, and it lists them all.
这个人给出了四条建议 都列出来了
Well, and it's not just one person,s132 people suggested those and 140 suggested this.
而且不只是一个人 有 132 人都给出了这些建议、140 人给出了这些建议
And so, if we try to plot this as this shows down here.
如果我们用图表展示这个结果
it doesn't end up looking super good.
效果应该不会太好
It's probably going to take a long time because there's a lot of gross stuff in here.
绘图可能需要很长时间 因为有很多数据
And so instead of that,
所以不应该这样做
what we want to do is basically break this up so that there's
我们想要的其实是把不同的建议分开来
a separate bar for each of the educational methods.
一个柱形代表一个建议
Yeah, see this is worthless to us.
你可以看到 这个图表没有任何用处
We can't do anything with this.
没办法观察到任何信息
And so, what we'd like is these are all of the possible values.
这里是所有可能给出的建议选项
And so, we just want a single bar for each one and then,
我们想要的是一个柱形只代表一个建议
we want to know how often people suggest that.
有多少人推荐了这条建议
So, there was this method of basically cleaning,
这里就是清理数据的函数
which is taking each of these.
其中使用了 possible_vals 中的值
And then, if we look at that,
详细看一下代码
we're basically just taking each one and then,
其实就是遍历所有的建议
plotting how often they show up.
画出对应的数量
That looks a lot better,
现在看上去好多了
and this function is sort of a nice helper for that.
这是一个还不错的帮助函数
So, I wonder if some of the individuals might have biased towards their own degrees,
接下来 有学位的人是否倾向于推荐别人获取学位?
complete the function below that will apply to
完成下面的函数
the elements of the formal education column in df.
该函数的参数是 df 中 FormalEducation 列的元素项
So, it says it wants the formal ed string
需要传入 formal_ed_str
which is a string of one of the values for the formal education,
也就是 FormalEducation 列中每个值 以字符串的形式
and then it returns one if the string is in this and a zero otherwise.
如果输入的学历是这些中的一个则返回 1 否则返回 0
So, if formal_ed_str is in masters.
也就是说 如果 formal_ed_str ……
so I'm just going to rip this part.
直接复制粘贴
Put in here then return one,
如果在这个集合中 就返回 1
else return zero, return one, else return zero.
否则返回 0
And basically, it's going to apply that to the formal education.
然后将这个函数应用到 FormalEducation 列
So, you can see one of them had one of these Professional,
你可以看到 这里有一个人的学历属于硕士、博士或者专业学位
And so, you can get an idea of what this is going to try to do but basically,
应该可以大致了解这个问题是想要做什么了
we're looking at, did somebody have one of these higher degrees?
就是查看某人是否拥有这些更高的学位
And if they did, then we want to see if they might
如果是 那我们就想看看
have a higher push for other people to get those types of degrees.
其是否更倾向于建议其他人也获取同样的学位
Whereas, if someone broke into the field
换句话说 如果有人在没有这些学位的情况下
and they didn't have one of those, do they feel differently?
进入技术领域 他们会感受到差异吗？
So, does your degree bias you
你的学历是否会使你 更偏向于推动别人走上与你相同的道路
Yeah, and then, basically this higher ed is the function.
这个 higher_ed 就是刚才那个函数
We're just using that and then we're going to take this in.
我们应用该函数 然后获取均值
And if you wrote the function correctly,
如果你的函数写对了
this is just checking it again using that test file.
这里的测试结果就会告诉你
Now it says, "Subset the data frame to only those with HigherEd equal to 1."
这里显示 选择 df 中 HigherEd 等于 1 的数据
So, df and I want to subset with df HigherEd is that what this is named?
就是用 HigherEd 筛选 df 的子集 是这样命名的
Yeah. So, in this code,
对的 在前面的代码里
we created this new column called HigherEd and here they calculated the mean.
我们创建了这个 HigherEd 列 然后在这里算出了其均值
They didn't actually show it but they just showed that it matched.
虽然没有显示出来 但是至少提示了这个答案是正确的
And if we wanted to, we could also maybe just print that to make more sense out of this.
如果想要的话 其实也可以把结果打印出来
Yeah, so it looks like about 23 percent of the individuals in
看上去 数据中 23% 的人拥有
this data set did earn one of those more advanced degrees.
三个高等学历中的一个
And here, we're going to subset the data set.
在这里 我们选择相应的数据子集
So, to those that are one and
ed_1 应该是 HigherEd 等于 1 的数据
then ed zero is basically going to be those that were zero.
ed_0 应该是 HigherEd 等于 0 的数据
And then here, we're going to just print these to make sure it looks like we expect.
再把结果打印出来 确保符合预期
Yeah. So, the top one should be only those with
好的 前面的应该全都是 1
one so we're basically just printing the ed one and if these are all ones,
我们就是打印出了 ed_1 的 5 条数据 如果都是 1
then that's what we'd expect because we subseted it to be only the ones,
那么就符合预期 因为筛选的就是 HigherEd 为 1 的数据子集
and the second ones only zeros.
然后第二个也全部都是 0
If there were ones or zeros mixed into this,
如果得到的结果里 既有 1 又有 0
that would be different than what we might expect.
那就与预期不符了
And then, let's see,
我们继续
this is a lot of code and it builds this cool plot.
这里有很多的代码 其实就是在绘制图表
It says, "You can check out this link here."
注释说 你可以查看这里的链接
So, this was the link that was used to basically create this plot.
其可以告诉你绘制图表的一些技巧
But this is pretty cool here.
这里看上去真的很赞
So, this gives us some pretty useful insights and basically,
这个图表提供了有用的见解
the red bars suggest that there are slight,
红色的柱形表示……
so the size of the bar suggests how much it leans in one way versus the other,
柱形的大小展示了倾向差异程度
versus these two groups.
针对两种人群
So, basically the percentage of people who were in the one category,
那些有高等学历的人
who suggested taking online courses is 20.5 percent.
推荐网络课程的百分比为 20.5%
And the percentage of those who were,
而那些没有高等学历的人
who suggested taking online courses was 21 percent which
则有 21% 的人推荐上网络课程
suggests that those who didn't earn one of the higher degrees were slightly larger.
也就说那些没有高学历的人更倾向于推荐网络课程
But you can see this green bar here is the largest of all of them.
这里还有一个差距非常明显的绿色柱形
It's substantially larger than the rest of the bars which are 0.007 and says five zero,
比其他所有的差距都要大 比如上面的 0.007 等
All of these are super small and then this one's
其他的差距都非常小
a full two and a half percent in comparison.
但这一个则相差 2.5% 左右
So, the rest of these don't even hit like one percent.
其他的甚至都没有到 1%
But this one hits 2.5 percent.
这里的却达到了 2.5%
And you can see that it's associated with a Master's degree.
可以看到这里对应的建议是硕士学位
So essentially, people who earned higher degrees suggest that the next step
也就是说 那些学历高的人推荐
for this person should be to go get a Master's degree where those who didn't do that,
继续读一个硕士学位 而在那些没有学位的人里面
that's only three percent of them suggests that,
则只有 3% 的人推荐读硕士学位
a two and a half percent difference
2.5% 的差距在所有建议的差距中是最大的
So, then it says "What can you conclude from the plot above?"
接下来的问题是 从上面的图表中 你能得出什么结论?
And essentially here we should,
看看这里
if we run this.
如果我们运行这里的代码
Let's see, so this says not quite right.
可以看到结果不对
So, there are some falses in here,
这里有好几个 False
and basically, we should change these to true or false.
基本上就是要将正确的结论修改为 True
So, everyone should get a higher level of formal education.
每个人都应该有高学历
Well, I think that the results kind of argue that
我认为这个结论不太对
you should choose the path that's best for yourself regardless of formal education.
每个人都应该选择最适合自己的路线 而不是只追求高学历
Online courses are the top suggested form of education and that's actually true as well.
网络课程是被推荐最多的学习方式 这个应该是对的
I said something that suggested this was false and then change it to true.
这里之前改错了 应该是 False
Regardless of formal education,
不管什么学历
online courses are the top suggested.
推荐网络课程的人数都是最多的
So, yeah, taking online courses was the highest for either of
是的 网络课程 两类群体的人都非常推荐
There is less than a one percent difference between suggestions for
两类人群对学习方式的推荐差距都小于 1%
And that's not true because we saw this two and a half percent difference
这个不对 我们看到了这里有一个 2.5% 的差距
And then, those with higher formal education
有高学历的人 更倾向于推荐别人获取高学历
And that is true.
这个是正确的
Cool, and so that looks great.
赞 我们都答对了
And that concludes this notebook.
这个 Notebook 讲完了